Guide to the Wesley Clair Mitchell Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: [B]. Business Cycles, (4 Boxes: Boxes 4-6; 33)
  - 1944 Dec 13; hol 2 p; "’The’ causes of recessions". (Box 6)
  - 1946 October 14; printed 3 p.; review by G. Soule of MBC (Box 6)
  - 1. hol 1 p; table: expansion to revival changes (various series) (Box 33, Folder B29)
  - 2. hol 5 p; notes and table: order of troughs in 1920-21, financial readjustments. (Box 33, Folder B30)
  - 2. hol 1 p; suggestion on non-fluctuating series (Persons, Ogburn). (Box 33, Folder B31)
  - 1942 Oct 23; hol 3 p; BC; 6th lecture; equilibrium. (Box 33)
  - 4. hol 1p.; business cycles and rapidly growing industries. (Box 33, Folder B32)
  - 5. hol 1 p; notes on Slichter's report on employment for SSRC [by WCM?]. (Box 33, Folder B165)
  - 6. hol 1 p; table: leads and legs at revival. (Box 33, Folder B33)
  - 7. hol 1 p; method of computing lags. (Box 33, Folder B34)
  - 8. hol 1 p; purchasing power expansion and production increases in revival. (Box 33, Folder B37)
  - 9 hol 1 p; workingman money stocks in prosperity and depression. (Box 33, Folder B36)
  - 10. hol 1 p; lag in incomes behind money volumes of production. (Box 33, Folder B40)
  - 11. hol 1 p; reference cycle patterns of non-conforming cycles. (Box 33, Folder B41)
  - 12. hol 3 p; charts: reference cycle patterns of pig iron production 1885-1927. (Box 33, Folder B42)
  - 13. typed 1 p; funds available for saving and investment in 1919 (D. Friday). (Box 33, Folder B43)
  - 14 carbon, typed, hol 9 p; statistics on consumption (family budgets), prices (index numbers) in U.S. and Britain [part for MUIN?]. (Box 33, Folder B166)
  - 15 hol 1 p; list of series and series groupings. (Box 33, Folder B44)
  - 16. hol 9 p; table: references, trough average leads and lags. (Box 33, Folder B45)
  - 17 hol 9 p; tables: inter- and intra-cyclical amplitude comparisons revival (averages and individual series). (Box 33, Folder B46)
  - 18 hol 1 p; cycle causes - specific cycle approach. (Box 33, Folder B47)
  - 19. typed 6 p; condition of national banks 1882-1914. (Box 33, Folder B48)
  - 20 typed ms 4 p; 113 "Summary of Price Classifications, Measures of Price Behavior, and Index Numbers of Wholesale Prices". (Box 33, Folder B49)
  - 21. carbon ms 26 p; Foreword to Russian translation of Recent Economic Changes by G. Safarov. (Box 33, Folder B50)
  - 22 hol 1 p; notes for rewriting (of J5C (27)?) - conditions of businesses (K. Dennison), monetary circulation. (Box 33, Folder B52)
  - 23 hol 1 p; notes on business administration, H. Dennison [for BC (27)?). (Box 33, Folder B53)
  - 24 1 p; notes and queries on various series; for or from A.Burns. (Box 33, Folder B305)
  - 25 typed 1 p; contents list of A. Atchinstein's Introduction to Business Cycles; notes by LSM and "G.M." (Box 33, Folder B54)
  - 26. hol 1 p; demand for cash in prosperity, hoards in early depression. (Box 33, Folder B55)
  - 27 mimeographed 27 p; NB reference dates, number of months in stages, inter-stage intervals, trough - mid expansion - peak - mid contraction intervals (for U.S., Great Britain, France, Germany.) (Box 33, Folder B56)
  - 28. hol 1 p; note [for EC(27)?] - profits and costs of production; Knauth. (Box 33, Folder B57)
  - 29. 1 p; control of business cycles. (Box 33, Folder B303)
  - 30. 4 p; "II Current Theories of Business Cycles; (1) Theories which Stress the Influence of the Weather". (Box 33, Folder B58)
  - 31. hol 1 p; notes - "Volume III"; interest and investment; cycles and long waves. (Box 33, Folder B59)
  - 32. [1906 ?]; hol 17 p; topics to be investigated in connection with study of business cycle 1890-1906 list of students and assignments. (Box 33, Folder B27)
  - 33. [before 1913]; hol 1 p; prices of producers1 goods. (Box 33, Folder B200)
  - 34. [before 1913]; hol 2 p; list of price series for fluctuation comparisons. (Box 33, Folder B201)
  - 35. [before 1913]; hol 1 p; directions for making comparisons of relative prices of raw and manufactured products. (Box 33, Folder B202)
  - 36. [before 1913]; hol 2 p; lecture notes; prices of raw materials. (Box 33, Folder B203)
  - 37. [before 1913]; hol 12 p; lecture notes; transition prices; attached statistics on railroad finances. (Box 33, Folder B204)
  - 38. [before 1913]; hol 5 p; early English crises. (Box 33, Folder B304)
  - 39. [("circa 1923"); hol 19 p; "Credit Ratios and Business Cycles"; talk to Robert Morris Associates. (Box 33, Folder B28)
  - 40. [after 1956]; carbon 9 p; accounts of railways and utilities for 1935 and 1956. (Box 33, Folder B254)
  - 41. [after 1959]; typed 2 p; description of data collection methods of J.C. Neilson Company. WCM notes on his reading and excerpted reviews and notices; undated. (Box 33, Folder B256)
  - 42. 1 p; abstract of M. Abramovitz: "Monopolistic Selling in a Changing Economy". (Box 33, Folder B99)
  - 43. 27 p; abstracts on A. Aftalion: cycles and - failures, industrial concentration investment, producers1 and consumers1 goods, supply and demand, pauperism, industrial accidents, wages, interest rates, industry differences, money costs, productivity, prices, general overproduction, cycle causes; abstract –Aftalion’s theory. (Box 33, Folder B100)
  - 44. printed 1 p; notice, W. Albig: "Recession in Industry Affects School Savings Banking." (Box 33, Folder B101)
  - 44. printed 1 p; review, L. .Amoroso: I Barometri Economici. (Box 33, Folder B101)
  - 44. printed 1 p; review, B. Anderson: "Two New Eras’ Compared". (Box 33, Folder B101)
  - 44. hol 1 p; abstract of Anderson: increase of demand at end of depression from manuscript). (Box 33, Folder B101)
  - 44. printed 1 p; review, S. Andrew and E. Flinn :"Appraisal of Economic Forecasts". (Box 33, Folder B101)
  - 44. printed 1 p; review, E. Andreich: Critique des Méthodes. (Box 33, Folder B101)
  - 45. printed 1 p; review, E. Axe and R. Houghton: "Records Show that Business Recoveries Precede Commodity Price Index". (Box 33, Folder B102)
  - 45. printed 1 p; review, R. Bachi: La Politica della Congiuntura. (Box 33, Folder B102)
  - 45. printed 1 p; review, J. Badert Arbeitsplanung und Arbeitsvorbereitung. (Box 33, Folder B102)
  - 45. printed 1 p; review, Banco de la Nacion Argentina: "Present Cycle of Railroad Activity". (Box 33, Folder B102)
  - 45. printed 1 p; review;, J. Barnes: Facing the Larger Problems of Business Management (Box 33, Folder B102)
  - 45 printed 1 p; review, Baudhuin: L’evolution Economicue de la Belgicue. (Box 33, Folder B102)
  - 45 p; abstract of H. Belshaw: "Profit Cycle in Agriculture" (Box 33, Folder B103)
  - 47 printed and hol 2 p; quote by V. Berridge: turning points - price and other series and secular trend; review: "Employment and the Buying Power of Consumers" (Box 33, Folder B103)
  - 46. printed 1 p; review, G. Bielschowsky:" Business fluctuations and Public Works". (Box 33, Folder B103)
  - 46. hol 1 p; quotes by L. Birch from "Theory of Overproduction". (Box 33, Folder B103)
  - 46. printed 1 p; review, O. Blackett: "Measures of Business Conditions in Michigan". (Box 33, Folder B103)
  - 46. hol 4 p; quotes and abstracts on Bonmation: cycle theory, long price waves, consumer goods price fall lead. (Box 33, Folder B103)
  - 47 typed and hol 3 p; quotes and reference to A. Bowley: "Relation Between Wholesale and Retail Prices since the War". (Box 33, Folder B104)
  - 47. printed 1 p; review, H. Brasch: "Realignment of German Business in the World Market." (Box 33, Folder B104)
  - 47 printed 1 p.; review, C Brossel: "Crisis in the Congo." (Box 33, Folder B104)
  - 47. printed 1 p; review, A.Burns: "Duration of Business Cycles". (Box 33, Folder B104)
  - 47. printed 1 p; review: "Business Conditions in Victoria" (anon.). (Box 33, Folder B104)
  - 47 printed 1 p; review, V. Bychelberg: "Domestic Sales as an Index of Business Conditions." (Box 33, Folder B104)
  - 48. printed 1 p; review, L.C.: "Crisis". (Box 33, Folder B105)
  - 48. hol 1 p; abstract of P. Cabot: "Interest Rates and Utility Stock Prices". (Box 33, Folder B105)
  - 48. carbon 1 p; quotes by J. Cardoza: crisis of 1837. (Box 33, Folder B105)
  - 47. hol 11 p; quotes and abstracts on G. Cassel: cycles and incomes and savings, interest rates and pig iron output, permanency of cycles, interest rate on German bonds, wagearners' demand elasticity for clothing, theory of cycles. (Box 33, Folder B106)
  - 50. printed 1 p; review (unsigned): "Changes in Pittsburgh’s Business Conditions - Some Barometers". (Box 33, Folder B107)
  - 50. printed 1 p; review, S. Chase: "Enemy of Prosperity". (Box 33, Folder B107)
  - 50. 1 p; abstract of P. Cherrington: "Some commercial Aspects of Styles and Fashions". (Box 33, Folder Bl07)
  - 50. printed 2 p; review, P. Christodulopulos: "Financing of the Beginning of Prosperity", "Cyclical Fluctuations and Stocks." (Box 33, Folder B107)
  - 51. typed 37 p; quotes by J.M. Clark: cycle remedies, price stabilization, supply and demand equilibrium, cycle and material and overhead costs, unemployment, credit, farming, capital, expenditures, labor as overhead, merchants' expenses, price changes and inventories, transportation, employment fluctuations and business size, labor efficiency in depression, railroad overhead, "sunshine movements". (Box 33, Folder B108)
  - 52. typed 1 p; abstract of H. Clough: weather cycle. (Box 33, Folder B109)
  - 52. printed 2 p; reviews, A Cole: "Statistical Background of the Crisis of 1857", "Statistical Background of the Crisis Period 1837-42". (Box 33, Folder B109)
  - 52. 1 p; quote by J. Commons: bank credit. (Box 33, Folder B109)
  - 52. hol 1 p. quote by J. Commons, H. McCracken, W. Zeuch from: "Secular Trends and Business Cycles". (Box 33, Folder B109)
  - 52. hol 2 p; abstract of H. Coonley: "Contraction of an Industry in the Business Cycle". (Box 33, Folder B109)
  - 52. hol and typed 8 p; quotes by M.M. Copeland: producers' and consumers' goods, operating expenses statistics, consumers' habits and marketing (Box 33, Folder B109)
  - 53. printed 1 p; review, G. Cox: "Another Year of Business Forecasts". (Box 33, Folder B110)
  - 53. hol 6 p; abstracts and quotes by W. Crum and H. Vanderblue: coal mining, banks, manufacturing, public utilities - and business cycle. (Box 33, Folder B110)
  - 53. hol 2 p; abstract of D'Abernon: "German Currency". (Box 33, Folder B110)
  - 53. 1 p; abstract of L. de Bernonville: Budgets de Families. (Box 33, Folder B110)
  - 53. hol 1 p; reference to 20th century Fund's: "Debt Adjustment Study". (Box 33, Folder B110)
  - 53. printed 1 p; review, L; Delgado: "Economic Cycles". (Box 33, Folder B110)
  - 53. printed 1 p; review, G. Demaria: "Studies of Economic Dynamics". (Box 33, Folder B110)
  - 53. 1 p; reference to H. Dennison: "Management and the Business Cycle" (Tp examination on back). (Box 33, Folder B110)
  - 54. printed 1 p; review, A. Dent: "Economics Research Work". (Box 33, Folder B150)
  - 54. hol and typed 5 p; abstracts, quotes, reference to A. Dewing: "Investment and the Industrial Cycle", "Creditors' Committee Receiverships", "Role of Economic Profits in the Return on Investments" (Box 33, Folder Bl50)
  - 54. typed 2 p; quote by Dibblee: cycles and firm size. (Box 33, Folder B150)
  - 54. 1 p; abstract of Senate Document: "Distributed and Undistributed Profits of corporations." (Box 33, Folder B150)
  - 54. printed 5 p; reviews, L. Dupriez: "Method of Computing the Line of Trend", "Method of Studying Economic Cycles and the General Cycle of Business in Belgium from 1897 to 1913", "Course of Business in Belgium from 1919 to 1929". (Box 33, Folder B150)
  - 54. 1 p; reference to W. Eiteman [?]: "Economics of Brokers" (Box 33, Folder B150)
  - 54. printed 1 D; review, D. Ellsworth: "Business Index Declines Sharply" (Box 33, Folder B150)
  - 55. typed 17 p; R. Engberg's indexes of agricultural fluctuations. (Box 33, Folder B111)
  - 56. 1 p; abstract of M. England: "Fisher's Theory of Crises", "Promotion as the Cause of Crises', "Economic Crises", "Analysis of the Crisis Cycle". (Box 33, Folder B112)
  - 56. printed 1 p; review, A. Espinosa: "Italian Economic Indices at the End of 1926". (Box 33, Folder B112)
  - 56. 1 p; abstract of M. Ezekiel: "Cobweb Theorem". (Box 33, Folder B112)
  - 56. printed 1 p; review, 7v. Foster and W. Catching: "Hissing Market". (Box 33, Folder B112)
  - 56. typed 4 p; quotes by C. Fraser: retail and wholesale operating costs. (Box 33, Folder B112)
  - 56. hol & printed 2 p; quote by E. Frickey: stock and commodity prices and interest rate; review: "Statistical Study of Bank Clearings 1875-1914". (Box 33, Folder B112)
  - 57. printed 1 p; review, A. Carino-Canina: "Economic Cycles". (Box 33, Folder B113)
  - 57. printed 1 p; review, W. Grabski: "Business Cycles, Crises, and Economic Development." (Box 33, Folder B113)
  - 57. printed l p; notice, E. Granovskii: "Theory of Economic Cycles According to 'Soviet' Bourgeois Economists." (Box 33, Folder B113)
  - 57. printed 1 p; review, E. Graue: "Relationships of Business Activity to Agriculture". (Box 33, Folder B113)
  - 57. hol 1 P; abstract of C. Griffin: "Evolution of the Automobile Market". (Box 33, Folder B113)
  - 57 printed 1 p; review of C. Guilleband: "West Indian Sugar Crises 1800-1930" (Box 33, Folder B113)
  - 58. printed 2 p; reviews: A. Gutfeld: "Statistical Analysis of Sales", "Economic Forecasting". (Box 33, Folder B114)
  - 58 printed 1 p; review, A. Hahn: "Stabilization of Business in Germany". (Box 33, Folder B114)
  - 58. hol 3 p; abstracts of L. Hall: "Relative Intensities of Secular, Cyclical, and Seasonal Fluctuations", Banking Cycles. (Box 33, Folder B114)
  - 59. hol 9 p; abstracts and quotes by C. Hardy: theory of cycles, cost of living rise and income, depression efficiency, different industries and the cycle, equipment length of life, raw material price fluctuations, influence of profit margins. (Box 33, Folder B115)
  - 59. typed 2 p; quotes by D. Harkness from "Agriculture and the Price Level". (Box 33, Folder B115)
  - 59. printed 1 p; review by A. Hansen, H. Hastings: Costs and Profits. (Box 33, Folder B115)
  - 59. printed & hol 6 p; quotes by R. Hawtrey: method, Webb's depression remedy, interest rates and international gold movements, interest and traders, cycle in France. (Box 33, Folder B115)
  - 59. printed 1 p; review, W Hay: "Consequences of mistaking Cyclical Expansion for longtime growth." (Box 33, Folder B115)
  - 59. printed 1 p; notice, H. van Hensbergen's "Notes from the History of Crisis Theories". (Box 33, Folder B115)
  - 59. printed 2 p; reviews, A. Herzenstein: "Do Long Time Business Cycles Exist?", "Capitalist Business Cycle in Marxian Light". (Box 33, Folder B115)
  - 60. printed 1 p; review, J. Hollander: "Panics and Pools". (Box 33, Folder B1156)
  - 60. printed 1 p; review, E. Hope: "Livestock Cycles in Canada". (Box 33, Folder B116)
  - 60. hol and printed 4 p; abstracts and quotes by J. Hubbard: "Building Construction in Recent Years", "Recent Developments in Federal Reserve Policy", "Open Market Money Rates",; review: "Business Volumes during Periods of Decline and Recovery". (Box 33, Folder B116)
  - 60. printed 1 p; review, M. Huber: "Economic Forecasting at the 18th Session of the International Institute of Statistics". (Box 33, Folder B116)
  - 60. Reprinted 1 p; review, S. Huberman: "Problem of Business Cycles under Conditions of Monopolistic Control". (Box 33, Folder B116)
  - 60. 1 p; abstract of R. Hurlin: U.S. prices 1813-1920. (Box 33, Folder B116)
  - 61. printed 1 p; review, M. Ignatieff: "Relationship between Circulation of Money, Business Activity and Price Movements in Russia". (Box 33, Folder B117)
  - 61. 1 p; abstract of M. Ingraham: "Professor H.L. Moore’s Analysis of the Business Cycle". (Box 33, Folder B117)
  - 61. printed 1 p; review, A. Isaac: "Investigation of Business Cycles from the Standpoint of the Study of Business Administration." (Box 33, Folder B117)
  - 61. hol & typed 4 p; abstract of H. S. Jevons1: on W. S. Jevons’ sunspot theory; reference: Causes of Unemployment. (Box 33, Folder B117)
  - 61. printed 1 p; review, C. Keller: "Barometer of the Business Cycle". (Box 33, Folder B117)
  - 62. printed 1 p; review, J. Kemenyffi: "Concerning the Possibility and Desirability of Business Without Cycles". (Box 33, Folder B118)
  - 62. printed 1 p; review, M. Kemper: "Economic Barometer, Business Cycle Analysis, and the Central Bureau of Statistics". (Box 33, Folder B118)
  - 62. printed 1 p; review, W. King: "Is There a Business Cycle?" (Box 33, Folder B118)
  - 62. and printed 3 p; abstract of J.M. Keynes: "Colwyn Report on National Debt and Taxation"; reviews: "Great Slump of 1930", Great Crisis of 1930". (Box 33, Folder B118)
  - 62. printed 1 p; review: N. Kondratieff: "Price Dynamics of Industrial and Agricultural Goods". (Box 33, Folder B118)
  - 62. printed 1 p; review, J. Kuczynski: "Business and Stock Market Conditions." (Box 33, Folder B118)
  - 63. printed 1 p; review, L. Kuvin: "Productive Overcapacity". (Box 33, Folder B119)
  - 63. 1 p; abstract of S. Kuznets: theory of business cycles. (Box 33, Folder B119)
  - 63. typed & printed 3 p; abstract of A. Lansburgh: "Excitants to Crises"; review: "Deflected Development of Business Conditions". (Box 33, Folder B119)
  - 63. 1 p; abstract of Lavington: "An Approach to the Theory of Business Cycles". (Box 33, Folder B119)
  - 63. printed 1 p; review, W. Lavonius: "Prosperity and Hard Times; the Nature of Economic Changes in the Life of Finland". (Box 33, Folder B119)
  - 63. printed 1 p; review, E. Lederer: "Limitation of Artificial Credit". (Box 33, Folder B119)
  - 64. 1 p; abstract of A. Lerner: saving - investment equilibrium. (Box 33, Folder B120)
  - 64. printed 1 p; review (unsigned): "L’evolution de la Crise Economique en Septembre 1930". (Box 33, Folder B120)
  - 64. printed 1 p; review, H. Lichtenberger: "Financial Difficulties of Germany". (Box 33, Folder B120)
  - 64. hol 1 p; quote by E. Lincoln: "Sales and Orders Indices and Forecasting". (Box 33, Folder B120)
  - 64. printed 2 p; reviews, E. Lipinski: "Methods and Work of the Polish Institute of Research on General Business Activity", "Problem of Increase of Productive Economic Forces". (Box 33, Folder B120)
  - 64. 1 p; abstract of W. Louck: "Price Margins during Prosperity". (Box 33, Folder B120)
  - 65. printed 1 p; review K. Madhava: "Business Forecasting". (Box 33, Folder B121)
  - 65. printed 1 p; review L. March: "Instructive Elements for Economic Forecasts". (Box 33, Folder B121)
  - 65. 1 p; industrial production statistics from G. Martin: "Industrial Reconstruction of France Since the War". (Box 33, Folder B121)
  - 65. printed 2 p; abstract of P. Martin: "Flaw in the Price System"; notice: "Technique of balance". (Box 33, Folder Bl21)
  - 65. printed 1 p; review, W. McKagne: "Does Canada Follow U. S. Trends?" (Box 33, Folder B121)
  - 65. printed 1 p; review, G. McLaughlin: "Industrial Diversification in American cities". (Box 33, Folder B121)
  - 66. printed 1 p; review, A. Mendelsohn: "Problem of Business Cycles. Structure of the Marxian Theory of Business Cycles." (Box 33, Folder B122)
  - 66 typed 1 p; quote by E. Meredith: agriculture and business cycles. (Box 33, Folder B122)
  - 66 typed 3 p; quotes by H. filler: "Earlier Theories of Crises and Cycles in the U. S. " (Box 33, Folder B122)
  - 66. printed 1 p; review, "ills: "Some Aspects of the Price Recession of 1929-1930". (Box 33, Folder B122)
  - 66. 1 p; abstract of H. Mitchell: "Index of the Physical Volume of Production in Canada". (Box 33, Folder Bl22)
  - 66. hol 2 p; abstract of W. Mitchell: "Industrial Cost and the Business Cycle". (Box 33, Folder B122)
  - 66. printed 1 p; notice (unsigned): "Monetary Element in Trade Recovery". (Box 33, Folder Bl22)
  - 67. printed 1 p; review, B. Mourre: "Monetary Tension and Danger of a Crisis in the United States". (Box 33, Folder B123)
  - 67. printed 1 p; review, R. Mukerjee: "Agricultural Cycles and Sunspots". (Box 33, Folder B123)
  - 67. 1 p reference to E. Nasse: Die Verhüt ung der Produktionskrisen. (Box 33, Folder B123)
  - 67. printed 1 p; review, N. Osinski: "Economic Depression in the United States" (Box 33, Folder B123)
  - 67. printed 1 p; review, G. Papis: "Monetary Theory of Industrial Cycles". (Box 33, Folder B123)
  - 67. printed 1 PJ review, C. Pearsall: "Industrial Fluctuations in South Africa". (Box 33, Folder B123)
  - 67. printed 1 p; review, J. Pedersen: "Conditions requisite for the Improvement of Market Conditions". (Box 33, Folder B123)
  - 67. printed 1 p. review, C. Persons: Credit Expansion 1920 to 29 and its Lessons". (Box 33, Folder B123)
  - 68. hol 13 p; abstracts and quotes by W. Persons: lags, barometers (WCM notes for paper on prices on back), credit expansion, Federal Reserve, stock prices and interest rates and commodity prices, differences between industries, own price index, iron and steel, from "Money Rates, Bond Yields, and Security Prices". (Box 33, Folder Bl24)
  - 69. typed and printed 5 p; quotes by S. Pervushion from Business Conjuncture; review: "Cyclical Fluctuations in Agriculture and Industry in Russia". (Box 33, Folder Bl25)
  - 70. hol, typed, printed 55 p; abstracts and quotes by A. Pigou: unused saving, Snyder and price fluctuation, floating capital, producers1 and consumers1 goods, psychological factors, taste changes, industrial disputes, periodicity, crop fluctuations, price rises and expansions, amplitude variations, construction investment and English cycle, wage rigidity, depression output and outputting impulses, cycles similarity, Turgan-Baranowsky’s theory, innovations, market spoiling, profit expectation variation, monetary factors, money making, secular trends - real wages, cycle remedies, general cycle theory; review: "Monetary theory of the Trade Cycle". (Box 33, Folder B126)
  - 71. printed 1 p; review, W. Plummer: "Effects of Installment Selling on Stability". (Box 33, Folder B127)
  - 71. printed 1 p; review (unsigned): Possibility of Forecasting in the Market for Household Goods". (Box 33, Folder B127)
  - 71. printed 1 p; review, A. van Rhym: "High Wages and Consumption". (Box 33, Folder B127)
  - 71 hol 1 p; quote by J. Riegel: labor efficiency. (Box 33, Folder B127)
  - 72. hol 17 p; abstracts and quotes by D.H. Robertson: labor efficiency, capital scarcity, consumers1 good peak lead, fashion and business cycle, Aftalion and marginal utility, consumptive industry collapse, sunspot theory, Hobson’s oversaving theory, large scale production and cycle, gestation period, general cycle theory. (Box 33, Folder B128)
  - 73. printed 1 p; review, C. Roos: "Mathematical Theory of Price and Production Fluctuations and Economic Crises". (Box 33, Folder B129)
  - 73. printed 1 p; review L Ruckdeschel: "More regional and local statistics!" (Box 33, Folder B129)
  - 73. printed 1 p; review, M.S.: "Economic Forecasting". (Box 33, Folder B129)
  - 73. typed 8 p; quotes by S. Schleicher: underproduction, wastes, wage rises and employer, labor turnover and business cycle. (Box 33, Folder B129)
  - 74. hol, typed, printed 8 p; abstracts and quotes by J. Schumpeter: history of innovations and cycles, depressions not cause booms, Pigou's theory, general cycle theory; review: "Mitchell’s Business Cycles". (Box 33, Folder B130)
  - 74. printed 1 p; review, P. Schwartz: "Circulation of Money and the Business Cycle". (Box 33, Folder B130)
  - 74. printed 1 p; review, W. Scott: "Economic Resiliency". (Box 33, Folder B130)
  - 74. printed 1 p; review, J. Schafer: "Explanation of the Business Cycle". (Box 33, Folder B130)
  - 75. printed 1 p; review, 0. Siegel: "Austrian Institute for Business Forecasting". (Box 33, Folder B131)
  - 75. printed 1 p; review, J. Sinz: "Business Cycle Research in Hungary". (Box 33, Folder B131)